Welcome to our favorite place to be to JupyterLab.
주피터랩의 가장 좋은 장소에 잘 오셨어요
Here we are again now in day three.
다시 대회 3일째인데요
In week six.
6주 차에요
I'm really looking forward to this notebook again and I hope you enjoy it too.
이 공책이 정말 기대되네요 여러분도 즐겁게 읽으시길 바라요
I've got some good things cooked up for you.
좋은 걸 준비해 뒀어요
So again, our plan today is to look at baseline models.
오늘도 기본 모델을 살펴볼 거예요
And so I'm going to start with a bunch of imports which are all imports that you've seen before.
여러 개의 import로 시작할게요. 모두 이전에도 봤던 것들이에요.
Nothing very new here.
새로운 건 없어요
But then some new imports in this second cell that you'll see here.
두 번째 셀에 새로운 수입품이 있어요
Some imports for traditional machine learning pandas that you have probably encountered many times in
머신 러닝 판다를 위해 가져온 장비인데 여행하면서 많이 보셨을
the journey, a wonderful way to organize your data into into things that are a bit like mini spreadsheets.
겁니다 데이터를 비트처럼 정리하는 훌륭한 방법이죠
Um, numpy, of course, I'm sure is old hat for you.
물론 넘피는 낯설지 않겠죠
And then sklearn.
그리고 스클론이죠
Scikit learn is a machine learning library that is incredibly popular, incredibly popular with tons
Scikit은 머신 러닝 라이브러리로 아주 인기가 많습니다 아주 흔한 알고리즘이 많아서
and tons of common algorithms that we will be using plenty of today, but most most importantly, linear
아주 유명하죠 오늘날에도 많이 사용될 겁니다 하지만 가장 중요한 건 선형 회귀입니다
regression, a standard part of any data scientist's toolkit for running linear regression models.
데이터 과학자의 툴킷에서 표준으로 사용되는 선형 회귀 모델이죠
And then there's another one here, which is a little set of imports related to natural language processing
또 다른 것은 자연 언어 프로세싱 NLP와 관련된 것들입니다
NLP, including Gensim, which is a very useful library for NLP related stuffs such as word two vec
겐심도 포함해서요 NLP와 관련된 아주 유용한 라이브러리입니다 아까 언급했던 워드 2 베c가
that I mentioned a while ago.
그 예죠
I mentioned just then and is something that is a powerful model for turning words into vectors.
방금 언급했지만 언어를 벡터로 바꾸는 강력한 모델이죠
So make sure that I run that cell too.
그 감방도 제가 운영하게 해주세요
Oh, and then there is one more, another set of imports.
하나 더 있어요 다른 수입품 세트요
Uh, more from uh, scikit learn again.
공부가 더 필요해요
But just I kept these ones separate because it's, uh, two different imports we're doing for more advanced
이건 따로 보관했어요 더 고급 머신 러닝을 위해 두 개를 수입하는 거니까요
One is for the support vector regression, part of the Support Vector Machines and package.
하나는 벡터 회귀 지원입니다 벡터 머신과 패키지의 일부죠
And then the other is the Random Forest Regressor.
다른 하나는 무작위 숲 퇴행자예요
Uh, we I mentioned random forests a moment ago, so we will bring that in as well.
어, 아까 임의의 숲이라고 했는데 그것도 같이 갖고 올게요
Okay.
네
Now this these set of constants, they might they might surprise you.
이 상수들의 집합은 여러분을 놀라게 할 수도 있어요
They they look a bit unusual.
비트가 좀 특이하네요
Uh, I'll tell you to hold that thought.
그 생각은 잠시 보류하세요
They will come in later.
나중에 올 거예요
You may recognize them if you've ever done anything like this before.
이런 걸 해 본 적이 있다면 알아볼 수 있을 거예요
That, um, slightly strangely, for various reasons that are very historic.
좀 이상하지만 역사적인 이유에서죠
Um, when you print a that particular symbol to the standard out, it changes the color to being in
특정 기호를 표준에 프린트하면 색이 변해서 초록색이
the color green.
돼요
Um, and for all sorts of, of reasons that I won't go into.
이유는 다 말할 순 없지만요
Uh, and reset turns the color back to black or white or depending on what your foreground color is.
그리고 다시 색을 검정이나 흰색으로 바꾸죠 전경 색에 따라서요
And so knowing these constants, having them to hand makes it easy to print things in color, which
이런 상수를 알고 손으로 직접 인쇄할 수 있으면 컬러 프린트가 쉬워지죠
we will be doing today.
오늘 할 거예요
Okay.
네
So run that constants run our usual environment setup that we know so well and log in to hugging face.
그러니 저 상수는 우리가 잘 아는 일반적인 환경 셋업을 실행합니다 그리고 얼굴 안기로 로그인하세요
Um, I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠어요
I don't think we actually use hugging face today, so I don't think I needed to log into hugging face,
오늘은 포옹하는 얼굴 안 써요 굳이 로그인할 필요
but we did it anyway just for kicks.
없었는데 그냥 재미로 해봤어요
Um, and then make sure that matplotlib comes in the Jupyter notebook.
매트플로틀리브는 유피터 노트북에 꼭 넣어주세요
Uh, we will load in our data from the pickle files rather than having to recreate it.
피클 파일에서 데이터를 로드할 거예요 다시 만드는 대신에요
And so in it comes, uh, let's just take another look at the training data.
훈련 데이터를 다시 한 번 살펴보죠
So let's just take the first training data point.
첫 번째 훈련 데이터 포인트를 보죠
And I'm just going to ask for its prompt to remind you again of what this was.
이게 뭐였는지 다시 상기시켜줄 프롬프트를 요청할게요
So this is I'm looking for the prompt attribute of one of these item objects that I really belabored
이건 이 아이템 개체의 프롬프트 특성을 찾는 겁니다 아까도 말씀드렸죠
Uh, in, in the past, uh, in the two, two days ago.
과거에요 이틀 전쯤에 말이죠
But hopefully this is now something you're becoming more familiar with.
하지만 이제 이런 것에 익숙해졌길 바라요
Let me print that so it prints out nicely.
프린트해서 잘 나오게 할게요
Um, there we go.
자, 됐어요
Uh, here it is.
여기 있네요
How much this cost to the nearest dollar?
이건 얼마 정도 할까요?
And then there's the title, and then there's the detail and there is the price.
제목도 있고 디테일도 있고 가격도 있죠
Now you might wonder why I'm spending so much time on things like this item class specifically for this
왜 이 문제를 위해 아이템 클래스에 많은 시간을 투자하는지 궁금하실 텐데요
And it is really because this is the kind of stuff that you'll be doing when you come up with your,
실제로 이런 일을 하게 되는 건 상업적인 문제를 해결하고
your when you face your own commercial problems and look for ways to engineer it and to massage the
데이터를 조작할 방법을 찾을 때죠
data.
현실 세계 경험이 유용할 거예요
You won't use exactly this code, the item class, and you probably won't have a prompt exactly like
이 코드나 아이템 클래스를 사용하지 않을 거고 이것과 똑같은 프롬프트를 갖지도 않겠죠
this.
하지만 이런 기술은 여러분이 복제할 수 있습니다 따라서 제가 내리는 결정을
it and understand the decisions that I'm making as we come up with it, so that you'll be able to do
이해하고 이해하는 게 중요합니다 그래야 여러분도 자신의 프로젝트에서
the same thing with confidence with your own projects.
자신감을 갖고 똑같이 할 수 있죠
So this then, is the training prompt that it came up with.
이게 그 훈련 프롬프트예요
And now let's look at a test prompt.
이제 테스트 프롬프트를 보죠
So I'm going to take the first of our test items.
첫 번째 테스트 아이템을 선택할게요
And I'm going to call the method test prompt.
메서드 테스트 프롬프트를 호출할게요
And remember that basically takes its training prompt but strips out the actual price so that we don't
기본 훈련 프롬프트만 갖고 실제 가격을 없애 모델을 테스트할 때 답을 공개하지 않도록
reveal the answer when we're trying to test our model.
하는 걸 기억하세요
And its job is to fill in that price.
그 가격을 채우는 게 그 기계의 일이죠
And if I want to know what it's supposed to fill in, um, I'll take it for a training point.
뭘 채우려는 건지 알고 싶을 땐 훈련용으로 가져가요
You take a train and then you can just call price like that.
기차를 타고 가서 가격을 부르면 돼요
And that is the actual price, uh, associated with this, you'll see that that this has been rounded
이게 이 제품의 실제 가격입니다 보시다시피 가장 비슷한 가격으로
to the nearest whole dollar.
반올림했죠
But the real price is something slightly different.
하지만 진짜 가격은 약간 달라요
So hopefully this reminds you refreshes your memory on what we're doing with these train and test,
이걸 보면 우리가 이 훈련과 테스트 메서드로 뭘 하는지 기억이 되살아나길
uh, methods and these these lists of training and test items and how we call them.
바랍니다 이 훈련과 테스트 아이템 목록과 그걸 어떻게 부르는지도요
So now I want to reveal something that I'm really quite pleased with, which is a chunk of code, which
이제 제가 아주 만족하는 걸 보여드리겠습니다 코드 덩어리죠 여러분 프로젝트에 정확히
again, whilst you may not use exactly this code in your projects, you'll do similar things.
이 코드를 사용하지 않을 수도 있지만 비슷한 걸 할 거예요
So it's a nice kind of principle, a nice way of approaching the problem that you should, uh, take
여러분이 해결해야 할 문제에 접근하는 좋은 방법이고 여러분의 문제에 대해
on and be able to replicate for your own problems.
복제할 수 있는 좋은 방법이죠
So I wanted to be able to test different models that we come up with in a really quick, simple way.
그래서 다양한 모델을 테스트하고 싶었어요 빠르고 간단한 방법으로요
Um, and that involves taking a bunch of our test data points and running them through the model and
그러려면 테스트 데이터를 모델에 적용해 결과를
being able to visualize the results.
시각화해야 해요
And this was something I used to have that in a function, and I ended up repeating that lots and having
함수에서 가지고 있던 것입니다 그리고 계속해서 반복을 했고 코드를 복사하고
to copy and paste my code a lot, because repeatedly I'd want to be doing the same thing.
붙여넣기를 했습니다 반복적으로 같은 것을 해야 하기 때문이죠
And any time you do that, it sounds like it's a time for you to build some kind of a utility to do
그렇게 할 때마다 여러분을 위해 일종의 유틸리티를 만들 때인 것처럼
it for you.
들리네요
Um, and so what I came up with is this, this class tester, which is going to be able to test a model
그래서 클래스 테스터라는 걸 생각해냈어요 모델을 테스트할 수
and the way it will work is that you will be able to write any function you want, any function that
있는 건데 어떤 식으로 작동하느냐면 원하는 함수를 쓸 수 있어요
will be called like my, uh, sorry, my prediction function or anything like that.
어떤 함수든 제 예측 함수 같은 걸로 불릴 수 있죠
And its only job will be to take an item and to respond, return the estimated price that is its job,
유일한 작업은 항목을 취하고 그에 반응해 추정 가격을 반환하는 겁니다 특정 예측을
and you put whatever code you want in there to do a particular prediction.
하기 위해 원하는 어떤 코드든 입력하는 거죠
And once you've written a function like that, you can just call tester.
그런 함수를 작성하고 나면 테스터를 호출할 수 있어요
This class I'm about to show you dot test and pass in the name of the function.
이 클래스는 . test를 하고 함수 이름을 통과하는 거예요
And it will take this function.
이 함수를 취할 거예요
It will call it repeatedly, in fact, for 250 different test items and see how good it is at predicting
250개의 다른 테스트 항목에 대해 반복적으로 호출하고 결과를 예측하는 데 얼마나 좋은지
the results, and then summarize that information back visually.
보고 그 정보를 시각적으로 요약하죠
That's the idea.
그게 목적이죠
And it's going to simplify our workflow distinctly.
워크플로우도 단순화할 수 있고요
Um, and this is the class itself.
이게 그 수업이에요
It's perfectly simple.
아주 간단해요
It's got some stuff to deal with with colors.
색상도 신경 써야 해요
I told you we'd be printing some colors.
색상 인쇄할 거라고 했잖아요
It runs a data point, and the run data point is the method that actually does the business for one
데이터 포인트를 실행하는데 실행 데이터 포인트는 하나의 데이터 포인트에 대한 비즈니스를 하는 메서드입니다.
particular data point, it gets that data point.
그 데이터 포인트를 얻는 것이죠.
This is where it calls the function that you provided.
여기서 당신이 제공한 함수를 호출하죠
It calls it with the data point to get your model's models.
모델의 모델을 get get 데이터 포인트라고 부르죠
Guess what your function says it should be worth.
함수에서 얼마라고 하는지 맞혀 보세요
And then it gets the truth by calling the price attribute that we just looked at just a moment ago.
그리고 가격 특성을 호출해서 진실을 얻습니다. 조금 전에 보았던 것이죠.
And then the error is, of course, the absolute difference between the guess and the truth.
물론 오류는 추측과 진실의 절대적인 차이예요
As simple as that.
아주 간단해요
It also calculates the something called the squared log error, and the formula for the squared log
제곱로그에러라는 것도 계산하는데 제곱로그에러의 공식은 여기와
error is exactly as it is here.
똑같아요
It's the log of the truth plus one minus the log of the guess plus one.
진실 더하기 1을 더하고 맞힌 것 더하기 1을 더해요
Um, and uh, yeah, you can in your, you can probably imagine why there's this plus one in the formula.
네, 그리고 왜 공식에 플러스 1이 들어가는지 짐작되실 거예요
It's because if the truth were zero, you wouldn't want math.log to blow up.
진실이 0이라면 수학을 원치 않을 테니까요 일지를 폭파할 거예요
So this formula works well for, for cases when, for example, the, the, the truth or the guess are
이 공식은 진실 혹은 추측이 0인 경우에 잘 맞아요
Um, and that gives us then the squared log error is the square of course, of this.
그러면 제곱 로그 에러는 물론 이것의 제곱이고요
Uh, and uh, we're then going to, uh, do a little bit of processing.
이제 비트 프로세싱을 좀 할 거예요
We're going to have the ability to draw a little chart, which I will show you in a moment.
작은 차트를 그릴 수 있어요 잠시 후 보여드리죠
Uh, write a report.
보고서를 써요
And this ultimately is the, uh, function I mentioned a moment ago.
이게 궁극적으로 제가 아까 언급한 함수예요
You can just call test to run this this test.
테스트를 호출해 이 테스트를 실행할 수 있어요
Okay.
네
Let me execute that cell.
제가 그 감방을 처리할게요
So you don't need to particularly understand everything that I did in this test class.
그러니 제가 이 시험에서 풀었던 모든 걸 이해하실 필요는 없어요
It's the the the principle of creating a nice little test harness like this and having it be something
이렇게 멋진 테스트 하니스를 만드는 건 원칙이에요 약간의 시간을 투자해 모델을
you invest a bit of time in to make sure you'll be able to get real insight into the results of running
실행한 결과에 대한 진정한 통찰력을 얻을 수 있도록 하는 거죠 비트로
That's the learning here.
여기서 배우는 거죠
So what's the simplest possible model that you could imagine?
가장 간단한 모델은 뭘까요?
What is the simplest possible model?
가장 단순한 모델이 뭘까요?
We're going to come up before we do real baseline models.
기본 모델 작업을 하기 전에 위로 올라갈 거예요
We're going to do two comedy models, silly models that are going to be the most basic thing we can
두 가지 코미디 모델을 만들 거예요 우스꽝스러운 모델인데 우리가 상상할 수 있는 가장 기본적인
imagine.
거죠
And let me challenge you for a moment.
잠깐 질문 하나 할게요
Have a think about what could be the simplest possible model, and it's probably going to be something
가장 간단한 모델이 무엇인지 생각해 보세요 아마 그것보다 더 간단한
simpler than that.
걸 거예요
Um, so the first is going to be two very simple models.
첫 번째는 아주 간단한 모델 두 개예요
The first one, I reveal the answer already.
첫 번째 문제는 벌써 답을 공개했어요
You probably saw that the first one will be we're just going to guess a random number.
아마 첫 번째 숫자는 무작위로 추측하는 걸 보셨을 거예요
That's all it's going to be.
그게 다일 거예요
So here is a function.
여기 함수가 있어요
Here is a function that takes a takes a it doesn't take a prompt.
여기 함수가 있는데 프롬프트가 없어요
It takes an item that not that it matters because it's going to completely ignore the item and instead
항목을 선택하는데∙∙∙ 중요하지 않아요 항목을 완전히 무시할 테니까요 대신
it's going to not care what it's told.
무슨 말을 들었는지 신경 쓰지 않죠
It will return a random number between 1 and 1000.
1에서 1000 사이의 무작위 숫자를 반환하죠
Uh, sorry, that's between 1 and 999 inclusive.
죄송해요, 그건 1과 999를 포함해서죠
Uh, we will set the random seed so that it's the same every every time that we run this test.
무작위로 종자를 설정해서 매번 같은 결과를 얻도록 할 거예요
And now we run it.
이제 작동시켜요
So the way that we run this test again is I go with my, my tester class, I just showed you dot test.
이 테스트를 다시 실행하는 방법은 테스터 클래스로 가서 .테스트를 보여드렸죠
And then I simply pass in the name of this function.
그런 다음 이 함수의 이름을 전달해요
I don't call the function because if I, if I call the function, it will just call it once and that
함수를 호출하지 않아요 왜냐하면 함수를 호출하면 한 번만 호출하거든요
I pass in the function itself like so.
함수 그 자체로 이렇게 전달해요
And now I'm going to execute this and you're going to see the results of my program.
이제 이걸 실행하면 제 프로그램의 결과를 보실 수 있어요
So it happened very fast because this was a very quick model.
아주 빨리 진행됐죠 아주 빠른 모델이었거든요
So I'm going to scroll back up and tell you what you're seeing here because it's a lot.
다시 스크롤을 올려 뭐가 보이는지 말씀드리죠 너무 많아서요
And it's something you're going to get very familiar with because we're going to do this a lot of times
여러분이 아주 익숙해지게 될 겁니다 다음 몇 클래스에서 이걸 많이
in the next few classes.
할 테니까요 get it
So each row you are seeing here is representing a different one of our test data points.
여기 보이는 각 행은 다른 테스트 데이터 포인트를 나타내요
And it's telling you what the item is over here on the right.
오른쪽에 있는 아이템이 뭔지 알려주고 있어요
Like here is a Godox ML 60 by LED, LED light kit, handheld LED.
이건 고독스 ML 60 바이 LED예요 LED 조명 키트죠 휴대용 LED예요
And then I cut it short after that.
그 후론 짧게 편집했어요
And what you're seeing for this particular LED light kit is what did the model what did this function
이 LED 조명 키트는 모델과 그 기능의 함수를
guess for the LED light kit.
보여 주는데요
And it guessed $143 because it's a random number generator.
무작위 번호 생성기라서 143달러로 나왔어요
What is the truth?
진실이 뭐죠?
Somewhat remarkably, the truth is $289, which is rather more than I would have expected for, uh,
그런데 놀랍게도 289달러였어요 제가 기대한 금액보다 좀 높네요 하지만
but only based on that that truncated Description there.
거기 짧게 묘사된 걸 보면 그렇죠
Maybe.
어쩌면요
Maybe it comes with a laptop on the side or something.
옆에 노트북 같은 게 딸려 있을지도 몰라요
So that's the error.
그게 오류예요
That's how much we this this model gets it wrong by this.
이 모델이 이 정도로 잘못하고 있다는 거죠
Here is the squared log error that we'll probably talk about another day.
제곱 로그 에러는 다음에 얘기하도록 하죠
But it's something that is meant to better compensate, better reflect the difference between absolute
하지만 이건 보완을 위한 겁니다 절대 오류와 상대적인 오차의
errors and relative percentage errors.
차이를 더 잘 반영하는 거죠
But we're really going to be focusing on this more than anything because it's so easy to understand
하지만 이 부분에 집중할 겁니다 추측과 진실의 차이는
for for us, for, for for humans, just the difference between the guess and the truth.
우리 인간에게는 너무나 쉽게 이해되니까요
Um, and it's colored in red because that's considered a really terrible guess.
추측이 형편없어서 빨간색으로 칠한 거예요
So red is really terrible.
빨간색은 정말 끔찍해요
Yellow is, uh, and green is fair enough.
노란색은... 초록색이면 충분해요
And the definitions for those, if we scroll back up, I've just come up with something that's a bit
그에 대한 정의는 스크롤을 다시 올려보면 경험에서
bit of a, of a rule of thumb.
나온 비트가 있는데요
I call it green if it guesses within $40 or 20%.
40달러나 20% 이하면 녹색이라고 부르죠
If it's within $40 or 20%, then that's that's green.
40달러나 20% 이하면 녹색이에요
You might think that's quite generous of me to say $40, but remember, there's a big range of prices
40달러라니 관대하다고 생각하실 수도 있지만 가격 범위가 넓다는 걸 기억하세요
here and you're just given the description of something.
설명만 듣고 바로 결정해야 해요
And really it's very hard to do this.
정말 어려운 일이에요
So I think if something guesses to within 40 bucks then it's doing a fine job.
만약 40달러 오차 범위 안에 든다면 잘 작동하고 있는 거죠
So you could of course be stricter if you wish.
원하신다면 더 엄격하게 하실 수 있어요
This this is all yours to tweak.
이건 당신이 손보면 돼요
But that was my principle for this.
하지만 그게 제 원칙이었어요
So here are all of the points.
여기 포인트가 다 있어요
And at the end there's a nice little visualization.
마지막엔 멋진 시각화가 있어요
So what are we seeing here.
이건 뭔가요?
I love this diagram.
이 도표 마음에 들어요
And we're going to see a lot of these diagrams.
이 도표들을 많이 보게 될 거예요
So so get used to this one.
Get in get에 익숙해지세요
The x axis is showing you the ground truth the actual value of a product.
엑스 축은 대지의 진리를 보여줍니다 제품의 실제 값이죠
Uh also sometimes you will hear that described as y by data scientists, whereas this axis is showing
데이터 과학자들이 Y라고 설명하는 걸 들을 수도 있어요 반면 축을 보면
you y hat as data scientists would say, or what estimate did the model give for the value.
데이터 과학자들이 어떤 값을 계산했는지 알 수 있죠
So we're seeing the model's estimate against the actual true value of the product.
제품의 실제 가치와 모델의 추정치를 비교하는 거죠
So the true value is always spread from from 0 to 1000in our data set, the model's value is all over
그래서 진정한 값은 항상 데이터 집합에서 0에서 1000인 사이로 퍼져 있어요 모델의 값은 사방에
the place.
있죠
A total random set of dots.
무작위로 찍혀 있어요
This blue line represents, of course, the line of of perfect guessing.
이 파란 선은 완벽한 추리를 의미해요
If the model ever happens to guess along this blue line, then it is guest exactly on the ground truth,
모델이 이 파란 선을 따라 맞힌다면 바닥에 정확히 게스트예요 운이 좋았다는
and you can see that it got lucky.
걸 알 수 있죠
Of course it will get lucky a small amount of time, and these green dots that are close to the blue
물론 시간이 촉박하긴 하지만요. 파란 선 근처에 있는 초록색 점들은
line represent where it's done fairly well.
get 작업을 꽤 잘했다는 걸 나타내요.
Yellow dots for where it's a and then red dots is when it has missed the trick and gone right out there.
노란 점은 A가 있는 곳이고 빨간 점은 묘기를 놓쳐서 저기로 갔을 때죠
Uh, so that was fun.
정말 재미있었어요
I hope you enjoyed it.
즐거우셨길 바라요
There's another very trivial model that we can do, and it may be the one that you were thinking of
우리가 할 수 있는 아주 사소한 모델이 또 있어요 제가 요청했을 때 여러분이 생각하셨던
before when I asked for it.
것일 수도 있죠
For a very basic model, uh, you may have thought one of the really basic one that occurred to me was,
아주 기본적인 모델에서 여러분은 생각하셨겠지만 제게 정말 기본적인
let's just guess zero for everything, or guess one for everything.
건 모든 걸 0으로 맞추거나 1로 맞추자는 거였어요
We can do slightly better than that.
더 잘할 수 있어요
We can take the training data set and say, what is the average price of a product across all of the
훈련 데이터 세트를 가지고 모든 훈련 데이터 집합의 평균 가격이 얼마인지 물어볼
training data set?
수 있어요
Because remember our model is provided with the training data set.
왜냐하면 우리 모델은 훈련 데이터 집합이 제공되거든요
So we can consider that as our as a as a constant guess.
그래서 그걸 계속 추측하는 거라고 볼 수 있죠
Let's just guess that everything is is the average price of anything in our training data set.
모든 게 훈련 데이터 집합에 있는 모든 것의 평균 가격이라고 가정해 보죠
Um, so basically we'll calculate the, uh, the, the prices of our training data set and then we'll
기본적으로 훈련 데이터의 가격을 계산하고 평균을 내요 훈련
find its average, the sum of all of the training prices divided by the count of them.
가격을 전부 합쳐서 그걸 개수로 나눈 거죠
That will give us the, the mean, the mean, uh, price of a point in the training data set.
훈련 데이터 집합에서 1점의 가격을 알려줄 거예요
And here is our very sophisticated model, our very sophisticated model.
이건 아주 정교한 모델이에요 아주 정교한 모델이죠
Again, it takes an item and it simply returns the, uh, the average.
다시 말씀드리지만 아이템을 선택하고 평균을 반환해요
So it ignores whatever it's passed and it just returns the average.
통과한 건 무시하고 평균만 반환해요
So let's have a look at what this is going to look like.
어떻게 보일지 한 번 보죠
Test to see if you can picture in your mind what kind of diagram you're about to see.
어떤 도표를 보게 될지 마음속으로 그릴 수 있는지 보세요
Uh, hopefully you can imagine exactly what it's going to look like.
어떤 모습일지 정확히 상상할 수 있으면 좋겠네요
And if you're ready to see if you're right or not.
당신이 옳았는지 확인할 준비가 됐는지도요
Bam!
좋아요!
This is, of course, the diagram.
이건 물론 도표고요
It guessed at a fixed point, which if you thought it was going to be at 500, then remember that the
고정된 지점에서 추측하는 거죠 500이 될 거라고 생각한다면 유통 방향이 좀 더 저렴한
distribution is skewed more towards cheaper items.
물건 쪽으로 기울었다는 걸 기억하세요
Not not as badly as as it was originally.
처음만큼 심하진 않아요
We corrected for it, but only a bit.
비트를 약간 수정했어요
Um, so it guessed this amount for absolutely everything.
모든 것에 이 정도 양을 계산했어요
And of course, at the point where that is the same as the value of the product, it got a green, otherwise
물론 제품의 값과 같은 지점에서 초록이 나왔어요 아니면 노랑이나
yellow or red.
빨강이겠죠
So there is the spread.
이렇게 퍼져 있어요
Uh, and you can see the result that you expected.
예상했던 결과를 볼 수 있어요
If we scroll back through the actual results, you'll see that there's a sea of reds with just some
실제 결과를 다시 스크롤하면 붉은 바다가 보일 겁니다
greens from time to time for things that cost close to the average.
가끔 녹색도 보이고요 평균에 가까운 비용으로요
Well, with that, I hope that you're enjoying it.
그럼 즐겁게 보시길 바랄게요
So far, we haven't actually looked at real machine learning models yet, but don't worry, we're just
아직 실제 머신 러닝 모델은 보지 못했지만 곧 볼 테니 걱정
about to do that.
마세요
Hang on in there.
조금만 참아요
See you next time.
다음에 봐요